♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ next Sunday, A.D. ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ he worked
at gizmonic institute ♪
♪ just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ he did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ but his bosses
didn't like him
so they shot him into space ♪
♪ we'll send him
cheesy movies ♪
- ♪ the worst we can find ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ he'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
- ♪ and we'll monitor his mind ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ now, keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
- ♪ where the movies
begin or end ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ to make his robot friends ♪
Let's go.
- Cambot.
- Pan left.
Hi, girl.
What a cool guy.
A wisecracker.
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
- ♪ and other science facts ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ then repeat to yourself,
"it's just a show ♪
♪ "I should really
just relax ♪
♪ for mystery
science theater 3000" ♪
Uh, no, I can't eat cheese.
It blocks me up like you wou--
- shh. [Clears throat]
- Oh. Hi there.
Crow t. Robot here
with Tom Servo--
- hi.
- ...On the satellite of love,
and we're about to enjoy
our lunches our moms
or our dads made for us.
Joel's down in the galley
'cause gypsy's on
a hot lunch program,
so he's making her a sloppy Joe
and tater tots.
- Mmm.
- [Computer]
Commercial sign in 30 seconds.
- Recess is at 1:00.
- And Servo's trying to palm off
his crummy Bologna and cheese
on white bread
for my chicken leg.
- Nothing doing, Tommy!
- Okay, forget the sandwich.
- What else you got in there?
- Uh, let's see.
Peanut butter
and gamy forcemeat,
uh, half an apple,
bag of barbecue chips,
and, oh,
one of those jock shakes.
Hey, a whole stick of butter
in every can.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
I can't have that.
My dad says I'm too husky,
so I've got one of those--
one of those fat-free
creamy snack loaves.
Yuck! They taste like
a chocolate-covered urinal cake.
Commercial sign
in 15 seconds.
Hey, uh, what's
that piece of paper?
- What? Oh, nothing.
- Oh, hey, come on.
- It's a note
from your mom, right?
- Oh, maybe.
Hey, what's it say?
What's it say?
Okay, okay.
It says, "I love you.
You make me so proud."
Okay? Are you satisfied?
- [Crying]
- Aw, commercial sign
in five, four, three, two.
- Commercial sign now.
- Servo, you don't have
a mother.
What?
[Hysterical sobbing]
Oops.
- [Tom Servo crying out]
- I thought I told you guys
that if you're gonna
play school lunch,
- ...don't use real food.
- [Coughing]
- Ick. And you know that
you shouldn't be eating cheese.
- I'm sorry.
It blocks you up
in the worst way.
But, Joel,
it wasn't real cheese.
It was American cheese.
I thought it'd be okay.
- Oh. Oh, great.
- I'm sorry.
Now the evil overlords
are calling.
So, packing your little pals
with food additives, eh, bubbie?
Well, we'll start the invention
exchange rolling wi--
- frank!
- [Muffled muttering]
Would you stop clogging
your colon with food
and go and get
today's invention?
- [Muffled muttering]
- Now!
And wipe your hands.
If I see a smudge,
I will have you destroyed.
Well, inchworm, I have to gloat.
We've been commissioned
by psychology today
to come up with a design
for a new centerfold.
Thank you, frank.
And frank and I have developed
a sort of racy rorschach
to appeal to
the Hannibal Lecter set.
Feast your eyes on this.
Say, who's the new girl?
Hubba hubba.
[Chuckles]
And it even has
biographical information
on the back.
Look. "Turn-ons: Group therapy
and big pecs.
"Turn-offs: Smoking,
codependence,
fat, greasy jungians who sweat."
Well, take a look
at this one, frank.
Think you'll be impressed.
I know the staples
ruin the effect.
Mother. Mother!
Mother! Oh, my god!
[Crying] Mother!
- Frank, she's hot.
- My mother's a Saint!
Well, top that, sugar-britches.
"Sugar-britches"?
- You know, sweet-pants.
- Honey-drawers.
- Yeah.
- Anyway, this is my
invention exchange.
It's based on the idea
that when people go camping,
they really need to bring
all their garbage out
of the forests
and keep the planet clean
and stuff like that.
Anyway, it's based on
the old premise
of the collapsing cup,
and it carries a whole
weekend's worth of filth.
Check it out. See?
Hey, that's cool.
Remember, take only pictures
and leave only footprints.
- Yeah. Give a hoot.
- Yeah.
I'm also working
on a porta-potty
that works on this thing.
- [Crow groaning]
- [Tom Servo spitting]
What do you think, sirs?
You're going to need
a collapsible porta-potty
after you ingest this week's
cinematic bolus.
[Muffled]
It is called gamera vs. Guiron,
and it is thoroughly
indigestible.
Serve it up, frank.
Open wide, Joel.
Eat it, boy, eat it.
Oh, that's good lard.
- See, this just--
- [alarm blaring]
- Oh, we got a movie!
- [Robots shouting]
- Oh, boy.
- Oh, great.
[Laughing]
Guess who.
Hey, how do you pronounce that?
Uh, gur-ee...
Goo-- gungurion.
♪♪ [Dramatic soundtrack music]
♪♪ [Tom Servo humming along
to soundtrack music]
"Christopher Murphy"?
Boy, these Japanese
have some funny names.
Yeah.
Dr. Shiksa?
Up from the ground
came a movie that's crude.
Ew!
"Nags" to his friends.
♪ Mcmlxix ♪
♪ daiei makes the very best ♪
♪ movies ♪
not!
I hear he's up
for the planners guild award.
- Oh.
- Neat.
Pizza's done, I think.
Yeah. Shouldn't they
turn it down to simmer?
Ew.
Oh, this guy wrote
the get smart music too.
Oh. Right.
It has that feeling,
doesn't it?
And this guy's known
as "zak" to his friends.
- Huh.
- [Joel muttering]
Hey.
Tonight on the usa network,
a very special episode
of swamp thing.
- Do not bring your evil here.
- [Man]
Astronomical observatories
- ...from all over the world
caught an amazing wave.
- Ping!
- Whole movie's gonna be
a slideshow.
- Ping!
It sounds like
an irregular wave
that might have been sent
from outer space.
- Ping!
- Only neater.
Spin art! By Ohio art!
Say, what a dish.
Mm.
It all started here
at the Watergate building.
[Man]
Come on. Hurry up.
- What--
- [distorted sound waves]
Wait, wait.
It sounds a lot funnier
if you play it real fast.
[Sound waves continue]
- See? [Laughs]
- Well, for now,
we call it the Sony bigman.
- That's enough, Bob.
- Right now,
the waves have stopped.
However, we cannot confirm yet
if they are a message
from the spacemen or not.
Dr. Shiga, the same galactic
waves were caught in England,
- ...uh, last year, accordingly.
- [Foreign accent] England.
- Are they the same one?
- No. That was different.
The one before was from beyond
the solar system, we think.
- Hmm.
- But this one
is very much nearer,
- ...according to
our calculations.
- [Joel mutters]
Does that mean people on solar
are the same system planet?
- Mm, no.
- No. That's hard to say.
- You have that ready?
- Seems like it's pretty hard
to dub too.
- There's no--
- business like--
- ...air or water on the moon.
- ...Show business--
- ...like no--
- so no living thing
inhabits it,
- ...as you know for sure.
- Uh-huh.
- And--
- yeah?
- ...there are--
- we're waiting.
- Go on.
- ...No rivers on Mars.
- Oh.
- Yes.
- And on Venus--
- yeah?
...it has several hundred
degrees centigrade.
- We're waiting.
- It does?
- And the surface of--
- yeah? Go on.
- ...Jupiter is covered with--
- some of--
...frozen ammonia.
You got a little, uh--
- saturn is also the same.
- Mm-hmm.
- Get on with it.
- No advanced vertebrates there,
of course.
- Aahh!
- What do those waves mean?
Assuming...
- ...they come from--
- uh-huh?
- ...proxima centauri,
which is nearest to us--
- right.
- ...how long
will it take Apollo--
- mm-hmm?
- ...one of the newest
spaceships, as you know--
- things.
- Oh, no. Story problems.
I hate 'em.
- ...How long will it take us
to get there, do you think?
- [Men murmuring]
- As long as it takes you
to finish a sentence.
- 500,000 years.
- Ha! I knew it.
With a layover in pluto.
Gentlemen,
right now, even if
we received an invitation
from the spacemen--
- here.
- ...We can't meet them
unless they come.
- If you build it,
they will come.
- And it's only a dream yet
-... for everybody.
- [Mock laughter]
Ehh.
- [All muttering]
- [Girl] Are there spacemen?
Sure, there are spacemen,
or those waves
wouldn't have come.
- [Boy] Tom, come.
I see something funny flying.
- [Tom Servo mutters]
- Huh?
- "Something funny flying"?
Sebastian cabot?
- Look!
- Where?
- It's major Tom!
- Oh.
Hmm?
- What is it?
- Um--
a thing.
- Tom, it's a spaceship?
- [Kids] What?
- Huh?
- Hey.
- Oh.
It's just the desert storm
video game.
- Keen.
- Ed gein?
- Let me look too.
- No, no. Let me look first.
- Nah. You're a dumb old girl.
- Yeah.
[Girl]
Akio, let me look too!
- Stop bothering me.
- Akio, it's a spaceship,
isn't it?
- Uh-huh.
- "Uh-huh."
- But I can't see it!
- It came down near the river.
- And into the river it died.
- Come on. Let's go see.
- Okay, let's go.
- Take me too.
The river.
Push me in the water.
It's a beanie copter!
Oh, wow!
Looks familiar.
- Another king feature.
- Ooh.
I think it came down
on the vacant lot where we play.
- Yeah.
- [Woman] Akio.
- Akio!
- Oh, it's mother.
We will get scolded again.
- Oh, we're in trouble.
- Told you not to play doctor.
- Oh, madame butterfly.
- What, then?
Now, I thought
you were studying.
Looking at the stars again, huh?
Mother, we saw a spaceship.
You imagine it.
Don't stay up late.
You, too, Tom.
If you want to stay,
you better listen to me.
- Go on.
- Yes, ma'am.
But we want to watch
the stars every night to--
I know.
You want to find new stars
and name them
akio and Tom stars.
- Am I not right?
- Are we not mom,
or am I devo?
Some of the papers said
waves were caught
from the outer space.
Systematically too.
It might have been
the spacemen that they heard.
- So much about lately.
- That's why we're trying
to find which star.
They may be very civilized
up here.
More than we are
here on earth,
with no wars
or traffic accidents.
- Traffic accidents?
- And we'd never know that.
There's no such star.
- Behave, or I'll take away--
- your life.
- ...your telescope.
- Oh.
Grownups have no dreams.
[Imitating Richard Burton]
Don't start with me, Martha.
- Let's have a bottle of scotch.
- [Tom Servo laughing]
'Cause he-- well.
Come on.
No more foolishness.
- Go to bed.
- [Boys] Yes, mother.
- [Tom Servo whispering]
She's not your mom.
- Tomorrow?
Okay.
♪♪ [Upbeat soundtrack music]
[Tom Servo]
Hey!
♪ We're gonna ride
our bicycles ♪
[Joel, crow join in]
♪ we're gonna go
and have some fun ♪
♪ we're gonna fill our hearts
with love ♪
♪ when we ride our bicycles ♪
♪ when we ride our bikes ♪
- Pretty.
- Stop. Stop.
- [Quietly] ♪ bicycles ♪
- [girl] What happened?
The spacemen came?
- ♪ We're gonna go
and have some fun ♪
- [man grunting]
Oh, it's the goofy twisted man
mom said we shouldn't talk to!
- [Tom Servo imitating
karate yells]
- [Grunting continues]
Whew!
Oh, Patrick Swayze.
[Breathing heavily]
[Tom Servo imitating
heavy breathing]
- It's the gang of three.
- Oh.
- You will die, Joe!
- [Man grunting]
- Oh.
- [Grunting continues]
[Tom Servo imitating grunting]
Well, he's done for the day.
Who--
♪♪ [crow imitating
soundtrack music]
♪♪ [Joel, Tom Servo join in]
[Tom Servo]
♪ wah wah wah-- ♪ oh.
♪♪ [Soundtrack music continues]
♪♪ [Tom Servo resumes
imitating soundtrack music]
- ♪♪ [Crow joins in]
- Man, that felt good.
Come on.
Come on. Go on.
[All]
♪ why did they have to shoot
my scarf? ♪
- Those kids again. Hey, wait.
- ♪ I am a twisted lonely guy ♪
- Stop. Stop.
- [Tom Servo] ♪ i-- ♪ oh.
- Stop. What's this?
- Stop.
- He does look like
Richard Burton, doesn't he?
- Yeah.
- Mm-hmm.
- "Mm-hmm."
- Good morning, kon-chan.
- "Cornjob"?
Say "officer."
Officer cornjob.
Come on, honey.
It's all right.
My name is kondo.
- Master of darkness.
- Obey the laws.
Two persons are not allowed
to ride on a bike.
- Relax.
- It's because we're in a hurry.
- Shame on you.
- What do you mean,
in this early morning?
- I see. I think you're up
to something again, as usual.
- Cold.
- That's not true.
- Huh?
We are going
to find a spaceship.
- A spaceship?
- Yes.
Don't be silly.
- Doh!
- We saw it last night.
It's true. It came down
by the riverside.
- Into the river.
- I see, I see, I see.
I'll tell you what.
Remember, the next time,
if you are naughty again,
I'll shave your heads.
- Ew.
- Is he okay, or--
remember? Okay.
- Now take this back.
- Imperialist yankee dog.
[Tom Servo imitates
suction sound]
You can go now.
But walk, walk.
- Yes.
- "Walk, walk"?
That's good.
- [Chuckling]
- Oh, for...
I can't help
but love those kids.
[Tom Servo]
♪ let's watch the kids
go to their fates ♪
- ♪ they'll disappear
into the woods ♪
- let's climb from here.
♪ It will be days
before they're found ♪
♪ cornjob will be lame ♪
[Chuckles]
It's a little...
- [Crow] ♪ why must we sing
this stupid song? ♪
- [Tom Servo] Hey.
♪ It's getting
really an-noy-ing ♪
♪ we apologize
for it's lame ♪
[Tom Servo, crow]
♪ we are filled with shame ♪
- Ta-da!
- [Laughs]
[Joel]
♪ now back to our ♪
- Show!
- Sorry.
- [Chuckling]
- He started it.
Huh? Oh!
It's cool hand Luke!
Shakin' the bush, boss!
[Brush rustling]
Maybe it's a spaceman.
It's a space rabbit.
Oh, what a burn.
[Sighs]
What? It's only a rabbit.
- [With brogue]
That's no ordinary rabbit.
- It's cute.
- Let's go catch it.
- [With brogue]
Look at the bones.
- We can't, you idiot.
It's too fast.
- Yeah, well, you're a jerk.
- Come on. Let's go.
- Ooh.
- Ditch her!
- Doh!
- Huh?
- [Gasps]
Brother! Brother!
Uh, she just wants her mother.
Just keep going.
What is it?
It's a giant, original,
hand-hammered wok.
We were right.
It's a spaceship.
- Right. Let's go.
- No.
Gee, good thing
those steps were there.
- Yeah.
- Convenient.
- It's groovy.
- They can't get in.
- It's just a painting.
- I wonder if there
are spacemen on it.
- Maybe they're inside.
- Akio, let's go inside.
- Good idea.
- Don't go inside.
Aren't you scared
of the spacemen?
You fool.
The spacemen are well civilized,
and they won't make
such a trouble.
- [Joel whispering]
Come to us.
- Don't be so dumb.
Uh, remember, always wait
for the reverse angle shot,
otherwise you'll walk
right into the painting.
- Flatten your nose.
- Excuse me.
- Yeah. Boom.
- Hello!
Don't think that they
understand our language.
Don't be so dumb.
What are you talking about?
Enough with the witty,
articulate repartee!
I wonder what happened
to the crew.
I think they went out
for awhile.
[Tom Servo laughs]
Oh, boy! That's great.
Yeah, nice use of color.
Looks like a ramada inn
from 1968.
Hey, it's working.
- Imagine traveling in this.
- N-No.
- Isn't it great?
- Yeah, it's great.
- Now, for the countdown.
- Let's play pop-o-matic.
Stand by for takeoff.
- Okay.
- [Button clicks]
[Whirring]
Wait! I said "lunch,"
not "launch."
Standing by.
Okay. Let's go.
- 10, 9, 8--
- whoa!
- [All shouting]
- ...7, 6, 5, 4,
3, 2, 1, 0.
- [Whirring intensifies]
- Uh-oh.
My eyes!
[Girl]
Brother!
Brother, there's too many
of us dying!
[Chuckling]
It's Marvin gaye.
- Brother!
- He should really tell
his sister his name.
Yeah.
- Hey, it's moving!
- We're in trouble!
- Stop it!
- Decrease flubber, quick!
Oh, I saw this
on the last starfighter.
Brother, where are you going?
Mother will scold you!
- Brother will scold mother.
- You are naughty.
- What will I tell her?
- Naughty?
[Joel, high-pitched voice]
I condemn you to death!
I think it's beyond naughty.
We're in trouble.
It won't stop.
Not till the fuel runs out,
I guess.
Tom, you shouldn't have
fooled around with the switches.
- Doh!
- Yeah.
Yeah, but you wanted me
to stand by for takeoff.
Sorry.
Well, let's find
the mini vodka bottles.
Look.
- Oh, it's a bunch of Christmas
lights against a brick wall.
- We're in space already.
Ooh, that would be
really cheap, wouldn't it?
Yeah.
Who would believe that?
- It must be
a superior spaceship.
- Mm.
- It's definitely
not childproof.
- What's that?
Huh?
Uh-oh.
- Rock candy.
- Welcome to general cinema.
- Please dispose of trash.
- Meteors!
- Watch out! It'll hit us!
- It'll hit us.
Akio, change course.
That's what I said--
it'll hit us.
No, I can't change course.
Looks like they're on the sets
of shenanigans or something.
- [Screeching]
- Look! Gamera!
Ernest borgnine is gamera.
- Yay!
- Help us, gamera!
- Gamera!
- Come on, gamera.
Now, we've secretly switched
meteors with folgers crystals.
- Let's watch.
- [Laughs]
- That's good.
- [Mutters]
- Mm-hmm.
- Gamera, thank you.
Well, you're quite wel--
oh, cut it out!
[Laughing]
[Screeches]
Let's have a race with gamera.
I'm feeling really good.
- We shouldn't be afraid now
'cause we're with gamera.
- "Feeling really good."
- Right. Because gamera
is our friend.
- Right.
It's awfully fast.
Is it mach 3?
- No, that's not right.
- [Mockingly] "Is it mach 3"?
It's over 3.
Even Apollo 8, the moon rocket,
was mach 33.
- [Mockingly] "Mock 33." Eehh!
- [Muttering]
We'd leave the solar system
at mach 50.
- [Mockingly] "Mach 50." Eeh.
- Let's go, gamera.
- [Children] ♪ gamera ♪
- hey. Snappy.
- ♪ Gamera ♪
- sounds like
"the Vienna boys' choir
sing songs of gamera."
- It's the cast of Oliver,
I think.
- ♪♪ [singing in Japanese]
"Senorita gamera"?
[Chuckles]
Hirohito gamera.
- Oh.
- Whoa. Whoa.
- ♪♪ [Children shouting]
- Lost an arm there.
- You die, Joe! Thank you.
- ♪♪ [singing resumes]
[Tom Servo]
♪ this is really a fun song ♪
Hey.
♪♪ [Continues]
♪ Gamera can do
the hoochie koo ♪
Whoo!
This is great. Uh--
- just when it gets good,
we have to go.
- Ohh!
- Oh, this is so catchy.
- This album is available
in the lobby.
♪ Gamera ♪
- Let's go, gamera!
- ♪♪ [upbeat]
♪ Gamera ♪
♪ gamera ♪
♪ gamera is really neat ♪
♪ gamera is filled with meat ♪
♪ we've been eating gamera ♪
♪ shell, teeth, eyes, flames ♪
♪ claws, breath, scales, fun ♪
♪ Dr. Forrester
is kind of a jerk ♪
♪ and frank is really dumb too ♪
♪ we have to take part
in these lame experiments ♪
♪ but do we complain? ♪
- No!
- Yes!
- Huh?
♪ So we haikeeba
all over the place ♪
♪ and talk of
a thousand wonderful days ♪
Everybody now!
♪ Gamera is really sweet ♪
♪ he is filled
with turtle meat ♪
♪ now we have commercial sign ♪
[Chattering]
That was rich.
Ah.
♪ Gamera ♪
[Laughs]
- Hey, he's passing
on the right.
- Hey!
- Well, it is Japan, after all.
- Oh, yeah.
Neat turtle, dumb song.
[Laughs]
I liked it.
- Boy, uh, gamera's gonna need
an emissions test, pronto.
- [Crow coughing]
- Aahh!
- The turtle's playing chicken!
No, no, no, no.
He just tastes like chicken.
- Oh.
- Yeah, right.
- Gamera!
[Imitating boys]
Gamera!
- Whoa!
- Aahh!
- Oh, man!
- Gamera!
- Gamera hasn't flossed
since the eighth century.
- Gamera!
- He has adult breath.
- Ooh.
He's trying to stop us
from going too far out
into outer space.
- [Gamera screeching]
- [Equipment clicking]
- What are you looking at?
- Aah!
Hey.
- [Screeching]
- Hey.
Hey!
I wonder what happened.
Gamera's lost speed.
- The speed reader
is getting faster all the time.
- Yeah.
I wonder why
it's getting faster.
Because of remote control,
I guess.
- 'Cause it wants to go faster.
- [Screeching]
I'm done.
There's nothing more I can do.
Pan off me!
Thank you.
Tom and ichi pop the clutch
and tell gamera
to eat their dust.
Whoo!
Akio, look at gamera's
jet propulsion.
Gamera, keep it up!
Oh, no.
Gamera blew a valve.
- Uh-oh.
- Well, that's all for him.
- Akio, what should we do?
- Panic!
The spaceship is going faster
all the time.
- You wanna go faster?
- Gamera! Gamera!
Help us!
In space,
no one can hear you spin.
- Ooh.
- [Eerie whirring sound]
- [Imitating eerie
whirring sound]
- [Groans]
What?
- Oh.
- Mother!
- I just killed a man!
My, my, such a loud voice.
Where were you
without my permission?
- Mother, it's about
a big trouble!
- "Micro mission"?
- Did akio tease you again?
- No.
- Akio and Tom--
- "acio"?
...went in a spaceship,
mother.
- Don't tell me such
a silly story like akio and Tom.
- Get it right, dear.
It's true.
We found a spaceship
near the river,
and they went inside.
It lit up suddenly, and--
I see.
Akio's up to something again.
- No more sugar for you.
- Please, tell me something.
Don't you believe
in spaceships and spacemen,
you know?
- I've heard--
- no, I don't.
But the paper said
a lot of people
saw flying saucers.
Don't you know it?
- They are all made-up stories.
- But, mother--
- I'm not your mother.
- Stop it.
Study, or you cannot enter
a good school.
Mommy's just mad 'cause
she doesn't know... phonics.
[High-pitched voice]
I'll show her.
I'm gonna grow up
to break up the Beatles.
Aww.
I am in trouble.
How can I
make mother understand?
Uh-oh. I feel a number
coming on.
Uh, head for cover.
- ♪♪ [Tom Servo vocalizing]
- Poor boys.
I wonder where they are now.
♪ Somewhere out there is my-- ♪
Oh.
[Clears throat]
Sorry.
[Wind whooshing]
Huh?
Wow, they're on
the Howard Johnson's planet.
Well, here's a hundred-million
yen well spent.
[Chuckling]
- [Tom Servo howling]
- It's all legos.
- [Joel imitating siren wailing]
- [Tom Servo
imitating wind whooshing]
- Looks like they're doing
fraggle rock.
- Yeah.
[Tom Servo
imitating bird calling]
It looks like they left out
a couple of scenes.
- I think so.
- [Laughing]
- [Rattling]
- Hey!
- Hey-hey-hey-hey!
- Hey, hey!
Oh!
That's better.
Hey, Tom! Tom!
- We're somewhere, I guess.
- What is it, Martha?
Akio, we're safe.
Are you all right?
I'm okay.
Hey, look.
The hatch is open.
Then there must be air in here.
Look. We're all right
without any space clothing on.
I wonder if we're
back on earth again.
Well, let's go out and see.
Oh, another budget-minded
plot twist here.
I wonder if we're dead.
Akio, I wonder where we are.
We're not on earth,
that's for sure.
Is it Mars or Venus?
No. Mars and Venus
doesn't have any atmosphere
like we have on earth.
Luckily,
the atmosphere saved us.
This must be a big star.
And there are stars like earth--
- it's a planet.
- ...And we are the first
who found a new star.
That's right.
Wait. Be careful.
We were brought over here
by remote control,
and we have to watch out.
That is most certainly
a reason for concern.
- Incoming!
- Whoa!
Hey, a northwest flight.
[Laughter]
The planes are beginning to look
like the stewardesses.
- "Flight attendants."
- Oh, sorry. Sorry.
- Look.
- Sorry, everybody.
There's one there too.
But it's in different colors.
So it must be a space...
[Indistinct]
Now gaos will do
nijinsky's Firebird.
And I do mean "fire."
[Screeching]
[Imitating liberace]
Now, before I play the piano,
I'd like to tell you
about my brother, George.
- [Tom Servo laughing]
- [Mutters]
What should we do?
Huh?
Suddenly, I have to go
to the bathroom.
Hmm. Backwards.
Look. Their water's
running backwards.
- Makes you think, huh?
- Yeah.
You know what?
I don't think that's water.
Ohh!
Tsk. Ahh.
Ye-- hey.
Eh, they're in California.
That's the answer.
No water, earthquakes,
big, giant monsters...
Hey, it's spot
from the new munsters show.
- Say...
- Where's Bonnie Franklin?
I know, I know. Don't laugh.
They made me in a hurry.
[Tom Servo laughing]
[Growls]
[Screeching]
Hey.
- Here comes old flattop.
- Shh, shh.
- George Harrison will sue you.
- Ooh, yeah.
[Guffaws]
Started makin' my nose,
and they couldn't stop.
- [Guffaws]
- [Laughing]
- I guess he's spearheading
this attack.
- [Snickering]
You win. I can't fight you.
You're too goofy-looking.
Are you laughing at me?
Am I a clown?
- Do you find me amusing?
- Errrr.
I'm not laughing at you.
I'm laughing with you.
- Ooh!
- Ahh! That'll happen.
I shouldn't have done that.
Hmm?
Did you know that buddy ebsen
was originally supposed
to play that role,
- ...but the silver paint--
- silver makeup. Yeah.
- Really?
- Affected him, so he couldn't--
- he's got a leg up on him now.
- [Laughs] Crow!
- I know.
- Gaos is trying to run away.
I don't think so.
He's trying to attack
from behind. Watch.
- Perhaps. Observe.
- That one doesn't move at all.
- [Growling]
- How would you move
if you had a Swiss army head?
My sister's got a spoon.
My brother's
a plastic toothpick.
Ha! Go figure.
Ah. Here it comes.
Flying low.
Well, there's uncle Joe.
He's flying kind of low
at the junction.
That's not uncle Joe.
[Yells]
Gymkata!
Hoo!
- Whoa!
- Haikeeba! [Laughs]
- I'd give my right arm
to beat that guy.
- Doh!
- He's flying on a limb
and a prayer, you might say.
- Doh!
- He's going out on a limb.
He's winging it!
- Do something, Joel.
- Ow! Ow!
- Hey, look. Buffalo wings.
I'm just gonna leave it
on there.
Hurt me.
- Ahh.
- Whoa!
[Screeching]
[In foreign accent]
He says you "brade" runner.
You know, in Japan, the snout
can be used as a knife.
Ooh!
Ehh, quit while you're a head.
- Ohh!
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry! Aah!
[Guiron laughing]
Oh, that's his trademark laugh
we're hearing there.
[Chuckles]
- [Screeching]
- Oh, now he's a hood ornament.
- What a way to go.
- Doh!
Uh, slice thick for steaks?
No, slice thin for stir-fry.
[Guffawing]
Tastes like chicken.
What a monster.
[Guiron laughing]
Hello, Mrs. Greenstein.
I've got some nice cuts
for you today.
I want to-- uh!
What do you mean?
That's all lean.
Good lean. Ahh!
[Growling]
[Laughs]
I guess it's too smelly to eat.
- So are you?
- He's going back
to the place where he came from.
I hope he's not using that knife
on the formica.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, he's lost his contacts.
Mm. Hey.
- [Boys] Huh?
- Huh?
- Quick, into the porta-potty!
- Ooh!
[Ping]
Freeze tag.
Come on, knife-head.
Give me ten more.
- Come on. Push it! Push it!
- Come on.
From the hideous foundries
of Chicago cutlery
comes a monster.
Where did it come from?
- Please no smoking.
Thank you very much.
- [Akio shouting]
- The opposite switch.
- [Ping]
- Here in the orgasma-tron--
- oh, wow.
Huh?
So why is he bowing
to worship them all of a sudden?
[Tom Servo chanting]
Ungadunga. Ungadunga.
[Joel chanting]
Salama. Salama.
- Look, they've ended up
at pee-wee's playhouse.
- Hurry. Jump out.
Cool.
Knifey! Oh!
I bet he drinks cutty sark.
[Laughs]
I bet he listens
to "mack the knife."
- Okay.
- [Laughing] Yeah.
Now, that one--
he's hard on shoes.
Bet he likes sharp cheese.
[Laughs]
Thank you.
Next show at 12:30.
Thank you, everybody.
Thank you.
Look. The water's returning.
Niagara Falls.
Slowly I turn...
Oh, suddenly,
I have to go to the bathroom.
- Hey, you're a robot.
Stop that.
- Well, you know, the water.
Boy, he had to go
like sea biscuit.
- Okay.
- I'm not quite sure,
but I think we're on
a highly civilized star.
Moving instantly.
- That's great.
- Yes.
Okay. Let's investigate
some more places.
Certainly. Let us do that.
Here is an opening
which warrants investigation.
This could provide us
with interest
and maybe little paths.
[Chuckles]
Oh, let us be prudent.
This is
a precarious circumstance
which may bring forth
menace and jeopardy
with loud report.
It's great.
Why, yes, it is certainly
above the average
of its kind and magnitude.
- Okay.
- [Click]
What's that sound?
Somebody is here, I guess.
Yeah, someone who is shaped
like a trapezoid.
Hey! Anybody around?
Please answer!
We cannot answer
because we do not exist.
They won't understand
our language.
You know, they're spacemen.
- Akio, what if goblins come?
- Ooh.
- What should we do?
- Don't worry.
- Goblins?
- [Ping]
- Help! I'm being whisked
into housewares!
- [Yelling]
Tom, jump off.
Clap on.
[Imitates clapping sound]
- Clap off.
- What are you afraid of?
- The clapper.
- This one. Look.
- It's a moving corridor.
- I see.
- Ah.
- Let's get on it.
- Okay.
- This could lead
to further developments
in our adventure,
which we are having now,
as did the goonies.
Fries are done.
- Number nine.
- Oh, oh, oh, oh!
- [Pinging]
- Number nine.
Number nine.
Oh, looks like
they're in a bank.
Yeah.
[Pinging continues]
Hold me closer, tiny dancer.
Ooh.
♪♪ [Eerie soundtrack music]
♪ Ooohh ♪
Huh? Hey.
People watching a movie?
It's Michael Jackson,
and he's armed!
[High-pitched rapid gibberish]
Simon!
Theodore!
Alvin!
[High-pitched voice]
Hi, Dave.
[Mechanical whirring]
Hey, stop vacuuming.
Kirby works well.
- Looks like a set from Brazil.
- Cool.
- I think it looks
like David bowie's glass spider.
- Boy, it's wonderful.
- Maybe this is
the control center.
- [Tom] Mm.
[Tom Servo]
Mm.
- It's the biggest lava lamp
in the universe.
- [Ping]
Yeah, that's what it is.
It's the thing that goes "ping."
Whoa. Space babes.
Whoa!
Uh, welcome, pink lady.
Fashion forward
means future this season.
Mm-hmm.
Say...
Massive babe-age.
Can you tell us where we are?
[English accent]
You're in vidal sassoon London.
And if you don't look good,
we dress funny.
Uh-- oh, wow.
Can you tell us who you are?
No.
[High-pitched rapid gibberish]
We're the bangles.
- We're nail technicians.
- I see.
They can't understand
our language.
- Who can?
- Hmm?
They appear to be making
some sort of fashion statement.
- [Sound waves]
- Hello. Welcome
to Singapore airlines.
- We were waiting
for you to come.
- Oh!
Hey, how come you can speak
our language all of a sudden?
Look, this speaking machine
translates all kinds
of languages.
- Oh, boy!
- I can do my Spanish
assignment!
I believe science is advanced
here more than on earth.
- I guess so.
- Please tell us.
- What star are we on?
- What's the drinking age?
How far are we from the earth?
- We call this star terra.
- [Tom Servo whispering]
It's a planet.
It's on the opposite side
of the earth
where you are living.
Exactly like the earth,
with the sun between.
- Same size
and moving like the earth.
- Sandwich.
So you mean to tell us
that it's like a twin star then?
- It's a planet.
- I wondered if there was
such a star.
- It's a planet!
- I see, Tom.
On the other side of the sun.
They never see each other.
I wonder why.
Akio, this is a big discovery.
Right. So the planets
of the solar system
are Mercury, Venus, earth,
Mars, Jupiter, saturn,
- ...uranus--
- [Tom Servo clearing throat]
...neptune, pluto.
- That's nine planets
altogether--
- [Joel] Hey.
- ...and terra makes the tenth.
- That's right.
- [Screeching]
- Look, crow. Her biological
clock's going off.
- Yeah.
- See that?
Look. It's gaos again.
- What, are you defrosting
your planet?
- Barbella,
- ...he let it out again.
- Yes.
- Sounds like a deep
midwestern alien.
- Is your name miss barbella?
Right. And it means
"as sweet as a little bird."
- [Tom Servo scoffs]
- And I'm florbella.
It means "pretty as a flower."
- Ooh.
- Where are the others then?
De-- uh, d-downstairs.
- [Tom Servo chuckles]
- Ah.
Akio, look.
It's the same as before.
It's funny. The water
is running backwards.
It's against
the laws of gravity.
You're under arrest.
We're the gravity police.
Over here,
we control the laws of nature.
- And you still dress like that?
- You do?
What a superior civilization.
- You know, I look in
my telescope every day--
- compared to what?
...and I thought there'd be
a perfect planet
without work and wars
and traffic accidents.
- [Tom Servo laughing]
- What is his obsession
with traffic accidents?
- I don't know.
- [Growling]
It's that monster again.
- That's our watchdog, guiron.
- [Barking]
- "Urine"?
- We can control it
the way we want to.
- Urine?
- Look. Gaos is running.
Can you tell me
why there are monsters
in such a civilized place
like this?
Like wall street?
I'll tell you what.
In our world,
it was a well-advanced society.
We could even control
the laws of nature
with electronic brains.
- Let's roll, folks.
- Okay.
- But a mix-up in the computer--
- I was just getting into it.
- ...brought calamity--
- "calamity"?
- Calamity.
- ...And also made
uncontrollable monsters too.
Is that so?
- Hey!
- Welcome to my world
of bemusement
and childlike wonder.
- Hey!
- [Crow yells]
You think you got problems?
Try going through life
with a nose
like a makita sabre saw.
[Laughs]
My subject's asleep.
Let the magic begin.
One, two, three.
It's me.
- Hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Ta-da!
Joel, you didn't tell me
about this part. Oh! Ow!
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
Oh, that hurts!
Ow! Ouch! Oh!
Oh, my head! Ohhh!
- Ta-da!
- [Tom Servo continues
crying out]
- [Tom Servo muttering]
- Ta-da!
Hey! Hup! Hup! Hup!
Hup!
[Grunting]
- Ta-da!
- Oh! Hey!
And now, my life's work--
the resolution to the sawing
a robot in half.
- Oh!
- Ta-da!
Uh, Joel,
I got the maharishi yogi
on line one.
- What do you want me
to tell him?
- Could you just tell--
- oh, you wrecked
the reveal, crow!
- [Alarm blaring]
- We got movies!
- [Robots yelling]
- We should take this off.
- We sent out messages--
- just wreck everything.
- ...Several times,
but we received
no answer at all.
So, that must have been
the wave that Dr. Shiga
was talking about.
- Mm.
- [Tom Servo] Mm.
So those alive
got on a big spaceship
to find another star to live on,
but it fell.
- Looks like Frankenstein.
Look at her.
- Only we are left.
- Oh, yeah.
- Errrr!
But we found out
that a small spaceship
was still working,
- ...and when we called it back,
you two were on it.
- Errrr!
- Now we're gonna kill you.
- I see.
We can only live here
on this space base right now.
- And there's only one bathroom.
- Hmm.
- Take a look.
- Where?
Oh.
It will be getting colder
from now on.
Within five hours,
we'll be bound in by glaciers.
Goodness glaciers!
That's a cold planet.
Barbella.
Oh, good. They have
an instant cash machine.
[Gaos screeching]
Over here.
That used to be a city
a very long time ago.
Yeah. It used to be called
old Jack city.
Right now,
it's the monsters' home.
You two,
let's go back
to the earth together.
We'll have the hottest
prom dates of all.
- Hey.
- We'll check the ship and go
before it freezes over here.
- Geez, look at the time.
- Akio, we're really lucky.
- Right.
- Errrr!
Let's go
to the bathroom together.
- I think the short one
likes you.
- [No audible dialogue]
[Tom]
If only gamera could be here.
I think gamera
is looking for us.
- Could be?
- Gamera?
- The gamera?
- You will die, Joe.
- ♪♪ ["gamera's theme"]
- Hey, there he is!
- That's right.
The world's studliest monster
of them all-- me, gamera.
I may be ugly,
but I'm fast. Ha!
Like a good neighbor,
gamera's there.
[Growling]
[Screeching]
Errrr!
Alexander salkind presents
superboy,
the crummiest show
ever in first-run syndication.
- You said it.
- [Whooshing]
[Chuckling]
I'll paint any child
for $49.95.
- Did he lose an arm again?
- Yeah.
There's a restroom
above the control center.
Take a rest
while we repair the ship.
- [Boys] All right.
- But put the seat down.
Boys! You know.
[Ping]
- [Whooshing]
- [Joel, foreign accent]
Oh, wow.
She's made from liquid metal.
Turns into shapes
that scare kids.
Big knives and stuff.
Ah! Don't do that.
The ship only holds two.
- We don't have any room
for the two boys.
- I know.
And don't worry, because we
still have enough time yet.
- What does she mean?
- Before that,
I'll check if they are poisonous
or not to eat.
[Gasps]
She's a man-eater!
If not, we will
make them our ration.
Go and--
go and check the ship.
[Scoffs]
Hey, you're not the boss of me.
- I'm really hungry.
- Looks like they're
in the genie bottle.
- Hey, yeah.
- I can't believe
you're wearing this.
- Put that down.
- My hair's not ready.
The girls said we can go
as soon as the spaceship
is repaired.
I know, but won't they
be surprised to see
such groovy space girls
when we get over there?
- They're sure to get
boss recording contracts.
- Right, akio?
Hmm?
Akio, what's the matter?
Hmm.
Oh, no!
Akio cubed it again!
Hiney, horny, harnie, hermie...
Oh, that one.
He's on the mescaline.
Ew.
Now, my boy,
you have to answer
my questions now.
You mean now now
or later now?
Ne-ow.
Meow, meow, kitty meow.
Tell me, what would you like
the most right now?
- Well, it involves jell-o--
- ooh!
- Huh?
- Come on. Don't be shy.
- Oh, the Mike Douglas show
is on his face.
- What's the matter?
Come on. Answer me.
- Oh, no! He's a cop!
They're busted!
- I see. You're hungry.
Cops is filmed on location
in the winchell's donut shop.
The subject: Akio.
The victim: The accomplice.
I'll fax these recipe cards
to you.
I'll fix you something,
but answer my questions
until it's ready.
- Is it hurting you?
- [Quietly] No. It feels nice.
- I see.
- Does this bug you?
I'm not touching you.
Does this bug you?
Akio, what's the matter, akio?
I was dreaming about a donut
wearing a sweater.
Akio, what's the matter?
- Akio, why do you have
that glazed look on your face?
- [Groans]
- [Laughs]
- I'll fix that naughty kid.
Akio! Akio!
He's got his long Johns on.
- Ohh!
- [Buttons clicking]
Chick's got a spell on me.
You knew about gaos before.
But are there many monsters
on earth like gaos?
Not now.
Gamera got them all.
- Ooh.
- What is gamera?
You said it's looking for you.
Come on. Tell me.
- Look at her pores.
- Come on.
- Gamera is a friend
of children.
- Huh?
- Yeah, 'cause he doesn't know
any monsters his own age.
- Friend of children?
[Akio]
He always appears
when we need him.
One time,
a long time ago,
he saved a child in hokkaido.
His first friend
was the husky Kenny.
- He was a butterball,
wasn't he?
- Uh-huh.
Well, maybe this time
he'll drop him.
- Noonan. Noonan. Drop.
- [Tom Servo chuckling]
Boy, these were good
old times, huh?
Yeah, yeah.
[Akio]
Then gaos tried to eat
the children.
Then there was ichi.
He was a good friend.
[Screeching]
[Tom Servo mutters]
Almost all the monsters
had their hair cuts
done that way back then.
Yeah.
- I remember that.
- Ooh.
No, he doesn't look
like that anymore.
That's his high school picture.
I remember he attacked gamera
with a highway no-passing lane.
We've seen this.
Thank you.
Ah.
Now, what does that teach us?
What are we supposed
to learn from this?
- I don't get it.
- It's backstory.
And for you active monsters,
the active light males.
Yeah, must be a substitute
teacher today.
- We've seen this already.
- Yep, yep, yep.
[Joel, high-pitched voice]
Am I too tubby, gamera?
♪♪ [Tom Servo imitating
dramatic soundtrack music]
- What the heck is that?
- Say, that's new.
[Akio]
He saved the lives
of the two boys also.
I hate my job.
I'm sick of saving little boys.
Kenny, ichi--
who's next?
Here's gamera
at the tanning booth.
It's a turtle under glass.
Say...
[Chuckles]
Uh, maybe you shouldn't
do that, gamera.
- [No audible dialogue]
- [Crow shouts]
I see that, and I see that,
and I see that, and everything.
And I see that.
[Screeches]
Is gamera taking up gardening?
He's got a green thumb.
Give me those Ruby slippers!
[Screeching]
[Tom Servo muttering]
Oh, forget it.
What a rush.
Let's get outta here.
Hey, he's doing
his Mussolini impression.
[Tom Servo, Joel]
Duce! Duce!
[Tom Servo]
Duce! Du--
[growling]
You sang like a canary.
- Hey!
- Well, that's funny.
About love, the wondrous
Leonard Nimoy film
starring gene Wilder.
- It was so good...
- Come, friend.
- Let's tarry
on the cheese couch.
- I'm sure of it.
You know, I had a feeling
that I ate a lot of
mother's donuts at that time.
- I'm glad he didn't say "milk."
- Yeah.
Your mother's donuts
are really good.
My mother's donuts
are a Saint!
I'm hungry.
I'm starving to death.
- I'm thirsty.
- I'm itchy.
- I'm scratchy.
- I'm sleepy.
[Wolf whistle]
Can I borrow some nylons?
- How about the ship?
- It's okay.
We can leave anytime.
- That's good.
- And I'm giving it back
to you.
Prepare some food
according to the instructions
of this card.
- These are fun
holiday recipes.
- And use sleeping powder.
- Sleeping powder?
- Right.
And we can't waste any time,
because while they're sleeping,
we'll eat their brains raw.
- Ew! Ech!
- You mean their brains?
- Nothing on the side?
- All their knowledge
which is given to them
and stored up in their brains.
- It's brain food.
- We can use this knowledge
when we go to the earth
for our plans.
Uh, why are you rotating
the biscuit holder?
It's the same thing.
Like the bacteria over here
became a higher animal.
I see.
[High-pitched voice]
Mr. Drysdale,
Jethro wants to be a rock star.
Good afternoon.
I came to pick up Tom.
- It's Vanessa redgrave.
- Whoa!
- Hello, elza.
- Hello, inga.
- Hello. Thank you
for keeping him.
- Hello.
- Thank you again.
- Thank you!
- Hello.
- Tom went out with akio,
and they haven't returned.
- Thank you.
- I see. Where did they go?
- Does tomoko know about it?
- Hello.
No. And there's no use
to ask her.
I'm gonna jump!
Don't try to stop me!
- [Imitating body thudding]
- ...This nonsense about space.
- You said space?
- Yeah.
- Hello.
- Tom said that he wants
to stay with us much longer.
- Thank you.
- So he must have run away,
knowing that you're coming
to pick him up.
- Oh, hello.
- Hello.
That provides me with interest.
And for that, I thank you.
- He can stay much longer.
- Thank you.
- If you wouldn't mind,
please, let him stay.
- Thank you.
I'll pick him up
when he's 21. Thank you.
- Elza, please drop in for tea.
- Hello.
- Thanks, but I'm in a hurry.
- I see.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
Hello. And thank you.
- Thank you for going.
- Hello.
- Send him to Harvard,
will you?
- Take care of yourself.
Thank you. Hello.
Shut up and keep driving.
- Hello.
- And thank you.
- Why, tomoko.
- A good joke's worth repeating,
isn't it?
- They really...
Went away in a spaceship.
Oh?
Tomoko, can you tell me
more about it?
- My god, you're ugly.
- Yes.
Kon-chan! Kon-chan!
- Uh-oh! This is a job
for cornjob!
- Please help us! Hurry!
- What happened?
- Come on. Hurry.
♪♪ [Dramatic soundtrack music]
♪♪ [Tom Servo imitating
dramatic soundtrack music]
What's this? I hope these people
will be more careful.
Cornjob is on the trail.
Hopping down the corn trail.
What is this, zabriskie point
all of a sudden?
Just keep running.
Go all the way long!
Around the horn!
[With brogue]
Can you see it, Gwen?
A round table!
Go home! Go home!
Touch 'em all! Slide! Slide!
Whoo!
Right here. The spaceship
was right here.
- What?
- Uh, yeah.
Let me handle this.
She's really a mess.
- Tomoko.
- I'm sorry.
American aerospace
bureau announced
that flying sauces
were all made-up stories,
you see.
- Or just delusions.
- Yeah, so was Iran-contra,
honey.
So, tomoko, please,
tell us the right story.
But I'm not lying.
And I saw it with my own eyes.
- Uh-huh.
- Tomoko,
don't you know what
the Apollo spaceship man said?
That earth is the only
oasis in space.
- Stutter.
- There are no living things
elsewhere--
- my god, that kid
looks like she's 50!
- ...And no spacemen either.
But akio and Tom
went in a spaceship.
- Uh-huh.
- You don't believe me
'cause I'm old.
[Elza mutters]
You believe me, don't you?
Come on, cornjob.
Help her.
- New cornjob helper. [Chuckles]
- Yes, I believe you.
You're a good girl.
You wouldn't lie.
- Yeah, right. Right.
- I'm sure you wouldn't lie.
- I'm sure that
you're a good girl. Okay?
- [Joel] I wouldn't lie.
I'll find your brother, okay?
Thank you.
Today is a good day to die.
- Aw.
- Don't worry.
[Joel, robots]
Aww!
Ahh!
She looks like Michael stipe
from r.E.M.!
She does.
- [Guffawing]
- [Muttering]
- [Tom Servo muttering]
- Thank you, kon-chan.
It's okay.
I planted a bomb on her.
Tell me, are you taking
a child's word?
Ask the observatory.
- But, please--
- what do you mean, idiot?
I'm surprised you believe
such stories.
- I'm sure the kids must
be playing around this area.
- In this vicinity somewhere.
- Why don't you send
a patrol out and find them?
- Of course I will.
- But first, you--
- are you sure?
- Yes.
- You know that yourself
that pretending
to believe them is bad
from an educational standpoint.
- Hello!
- But can't you understand--
- thank you!
- ...How serious tomoko
is about all this?
- Forget it!
- [Tomoko] Brother!
Kon-chan is going to find you.
- Don't move!
You're on a mine!
- [Tomoko shouting]
She is cute
when she's looney, isn't she?
- Uhh.
- ♪♪ [dramatic soundtrack music]
- Please, god, save the boy.
- [Tom Servo] ♪ ooohh ♪
- Please.
- Why should I?
What have you done
for me lately?
♪ Ooohhh ♪
Did you hear someone
praying for us?
Sounded like my sister.
[Imitating Richard Burton]
I dreamt of a big pool
of scotch.
- [Ping]
- Hmm?
Uh, is this dying
in suds all of a sudden?
- All right! Sliders and bosco.
- Akio!
Texas chili burger.
Ooh.
There you are.
Hungry, aren't you?
- Mmm.
- [Panting]
- Oh, boy! My favorite donut.
- Really looks good.
- Donuts and gray water. Mmm!
- Look. They're just like
my mother's donuts.
- Yeah.
- Ooh.
Please. Please eat them.
Thank you very much.
[Tom Servo mutters]
- Wait a minute.
- You're not a cop! [Laughing]
- Oh, that's funny.
- [Joel groans, mutters]
Just can't beat that one.
- Anything wrong?
- Be still.
- ♪♪
- ♪♪ [Tom Servo humming along]
Akio, I thought
I heard gamera coming.
- Oh, no,
it's just the theme music.
- Huh?
♪♪ ["Gamera's theme"]
It's gamera, all right,
and he's burning oil!
Ooh.
He is too.
- [Screeches]
- Don't eat the donuts, kids!
It was too late.
The kids had nicked the donuts.
I didn't hear him.
It must've been my imagination.
- Look at their breath.
- Come on. Let's eat.
Man, it looks
really cold in there.
It's a spaceship.
They should at least
have a space heater.
Don't bite me! I'm alive!
Ow! Oh! I'm a sentient being!
Oh, dear god, no!
But it was too late.
The kids had crushed
the crullers.
Get the bear claws?
- I'll give you half of mine.
- Thank you.
It's the biggest thing
in the case.
Uhh! Soy milk mixed
with pineapple juice.
It's my backwash.
Ooh, this ipecac
is really tasty.
Ech!
[Growling]
I'm coming.
Oh, hold on.
- It's really good, isn't it?
- [Tom Servo imitating chomping]
Hey, there's half a worm
in here.
Oop.
I was kidding! I was kidding!
- Nice dive.
- That's funny.
Hey, you gonna
finish your donut?
- What's the matter? Wake up.
- Could I have that?
You gonna finish that?
[Ping]
[Whooshing]
Kids' brains always taste better
when they've been
thinking about donuts.
- The sleeping powder's
taken effect.
- Sweeter.
Come. Get ready.
Get your jumper on.
[Buttons clicking]
[Whirring]
Would you believe--
the cone of silence.
Oh, no. It's a hooded
weber brain cooker.
- Ooh.
- Gymkata!
That was neat.
Oohh!
Hey.
[All]
Weasels rip my flesh.
Rizzz!
Uh, she's into cranial graphics,
I can see.
Neat.
Set the razor for crew cut.
She's cutting his hair
with the yellow submarine.
- Neat.
- Ooh.
Now I suppose he's gonna wanna
sing "nothing compares to you."
Cut it from here
and remove the skull.
It's the best part.
Ooh.
[Joel]
♪ shave and lobotomy ♪
[Joel, Tom Servo]
♪ two bits ♪
Hey, it's a dremel tool.
- [Imitating whirring]
- You should have
safety glasses.
[Alarm sounding]
Get splattered with dura mater.
Oh, this always happens
right at dinnertime.
Uh, guiron's gotta go walkies.
[Ping]
That's a pretty typical picture
of Burton there, isn't it?
- Yep.
- Poor sap.
[Alarm continues]
[Tom Servo whistling,
imitating alarm]
I'm coming, I'm coming!
Hold your horses.
- Say...
- It's gamera!
They said he's a friend
of the children.
I wonder if he's here
to help those kids.
- Something else to worry about.
- That's right.
Let's take care of it first.
We can eat later.
[Button clicks]
Ah, six rms, river view.
Hmm.
It's a huge number 2 pencil!
- Wow!
- [Button clicks]
[Laughing]
[Button clicks]
Hey, you know,
the Japanese space program
is based on the blooming
ground flower.
Astronauts are launched
into space with loud reports.
Light missile and get away!
Thunderbirds are go!
Mr. Spock wants
his eye shadow back.
Let the monsters
fight each other.
Let guiron out.
Bring it in. Bring it in.
That's good.
[Growling]
Whoa!
[Screeching]
Hey, hey, hey!
I just got here!
Come on!
The cry eye.
You're so smart
you can't even cut
through a tin can.
Now try cutting
through a tomato.
Uh-oh.
Ew.
Uch!
Oh, that's sick.
Here. Wait. Wait. Here.
Touch me here while you do that.
Thank you.
Uh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
More of that.
Yeah, that's good. Yeah.
Oh, don't do helicopters!
They make me wanna pu--
[Gags]
[Screeching]
"Rocky mountain high."
Oh, he got a wedgie.
[Chuckles]
Look at him there.
Hey, you kids are gonna
take the edge off that blade.
Rock crushes scissors.
[Sniffing]
Hey, something smells good--
oh, that's me! Oh!
Ew.
Hey. Look at that.
Look at, uh, guiron emote.
Ooh.
[Growls]
Thanks for the pan.
Appreciate it.
- What?
- [Screeching]
- Uh-- he's all starry eyed.
- Doh!
Wow. Quick return.
Now, uh, this is supposed
to be good for my pores?
I just rub this in like this?
Okay.
I can feel it working.
Ooh, ooh,
it's starting to tingle.
Is that supposed to happen?
Ooh. I-- ooh.
Yeah, it's getting hot now.
It's really--
it's starting to hot
and burn and stuff.
- Is that supposed to happen?
- [Screeching continues]
- Poor guy.
- Ah, he's gonna need
a styptic pencil the size
of the Washington monument.
- I'll say.
- Oh, now he's doing
his Dan Haggerty impression.
- Oh!
- Ahh!
I know it's an old wives' tale,
but I feel better.
Haikeeba! Gymkata!
By Marx.
Ooh!
Ooh! Ooh! Oh, no!
That's not supposed to happen.
[Chuckles]
[Screeching]
Didn't expect that.
[Screeching continues]
- Aw.
- Hello.
Gamera's crying.
I gotta go julienne something.
Hey, check it out.
Party ball.
[All whooping]
I knew it was worth
the trip, man.
Cool.
[Screeching]
Take the nestea plunge.
- [Tom Servo laughing]
- Whoa. Wait a minute.
The planet of no continuity.
Suddenly it's gray lady down.
[Screeching continues]
Boy, he's sure underwater there,
isn't he?
- A lot of underwater dust.
- Really looks underwater to me.
[Imitating submarine
equipment beeping]
[Imitating sonar noise]
Take a picture.
It lasts longer.
Yes. That's good.
[Laughs]
[Sonar noise
imitations continues]
[Imitating Richard Burton]
Oh, god, I'm pissed.
Ooh.
Don't start with me, donut.
- [Gasps]
- Huh?
Hey, your friend
became a hare krishna.
Akio, what happened?
- Help! Help!
- Hey, little skinhead pal.
He's gone melon crazy.
- Gotta get a spoon.
- [Ping]
[Whooshing]
[Barbella]
Come on. Hurry.
Let's cook those kids, or else.
[Florbella]
Wait. It's funny.
There's something wrong.
- Gamera put the spaceship
out of order.
- [Clicking]
That's the only ship
we've got left.
- Wait. I got a free game.
- [Muttering]
Anyway, let's eat
the kids later,
and let's fix
the spacecraft first.
[Imitating Mr. Rogers]
Let's look at picture picture.
[Button clicks]
[Ping]
[Whooshing]
It's awful. Akio! Akio!
Hey, come on, telly.
Wake up.
You got
a player's club ad to do.
Okay.
- Ow!
- Ooh.
Hey, he's not
a three-minute egg.
Geez, you got a long skull.
You look kind of like Henry.
Hey, what happened
to my hair?
There's no time for that.
Those girls were cannibals.
- What?
- They ate my hair?
They were not fixing the ship
for us to go back to earth
but to go eat the people.
- Come on. Let's run away.
- But my head.
Here. Wear this.
[Laughs]
Go ahead. Cut loose, my friend.
[Ping]
- Hurry, hurry!
- You know, I'll never get used
to that thing.
[Whirring]
You know, even though
they tried to eat our brains,
you gotta admit
it's kind of fun here.
Yep. Here they are.
Ooh, the cars, Bryan Adams,
journey escape,
haircut one hundred--
ooh, that's an old one.
[Akio]
Tom, wait a minute.
Tom!
Why are those kids over there?
They're trying to run away.
Now they know about us,
I guess.
No, we can't let them
get away.
This plan of yours has quality.
It is good.
[Ping]
Floor, please.
Now, where'd they go?
Now, we're all dressed up,
and no dates.
[Southern accent]
Oh, that's them
over on fudge pie mountain.
[Ping]
[Whooshing]
Gee, there's a lot of traffic
here today.
- Oh, that was me.
- You! Don't think
you can get away.
Hey, what happened?
We're back again. Let's run.
♪♪ [Dramatic soundtrack music]
- Run!
- ♪♪ [Tom Servo imitating
dramatic soundtrack music]
- [Joel mutters]
- Akio, how did you do that?
- I pushed the reverse button.
- It's fun.
- Hey.
- Look.
- [Pinging]
Oh, they're going
to the guggenheim.
Oh-- huh?
- Manager to housewares.
- Hooray! They're gone!
Let's break the handle
so they won't be able
to come back again.
Okay.
[Effeminate tone]
Good idea, miss hathaway.
Sounds like miss hathaway.
- [Pinging continues]
- Vandals.
- Look.
- All right!
- Yeah.
- Cheese!
- Cool.
- Hooray!
Now they can't come back again.
[Pinging continues]
Sounds like the ventures
are tuning up.
Yeah.
You know, crushing cheese
should not be that hard.
- Doesn't it feel good to know
they can never come back again?
- Must be parmesan.
- [Tom] Yeah.
- [Joel, robots] Hello!
- Bad boy.
- You can spank us now.
- How did you get back?
- Since we broke the handle?
- The vandals broke the handles.
- Use your head, kid.
We made a round trip.
- Tom, let's run.
- Don't move.
Doh!
- Hey, let me go!
- We're not good to eat.
Yeah, I'm all stringy and gamy,
and an hour after you eat me,
you'll be hungry again.
[Tom Servo laughs]
Hands over your head.
- "Pants over your head"?
- Back to back.
Now dance.
- Switch.
- With Ellen barkin
and Jimmy smits.
[Whooshing]
Say...
It's a spanek vertical roaster
with the amazing
heat tower action!
- [Boys shouting]
- They're a kiddy cocktail.
[Barbella]
Hurry. We must repair the ship.
- Help!
- Let us outta here!
- Let us out!
- Help!
- Ah, dark.
- [Button clicks]
Shaken, not stirred.
- I'll take me, straight up.
[Hiccups]
- [Tom Servo chuckles]
Okay, so I lost your son!
- All done?
- Huh?
I wonder,
where did they go?
They even had
the police worried.
If they come back,
I'll spank Tom
thirty times as punishment.
[Tom Servo clears throat]
I'm Tom. Spank me.
- I'm very sorry.
- Hey.
It's not your fault.
I hope they return safely.
[Car horn honks]
Oh, there they are.
[Tires screech]
I just drove up and--
oh, no.
- Where's that little girl?
- There she is.
- [Reporters chattering]
- Damn the paparazzi.
[Man]
Come here. Tell us about
that spaceship that you saw.
Right? Come on. Tell me.
Come on. Tell me.
- "Come on." Newspaper robot.
- Who are you?
- Hello.
- We were hoping you'd know.
- Thank you.
- The observation report said
that a spaceship flew up
near here this morning.
We received a report
from the police too,
so we want to make sure
about the boys.
- Wait a minute! You're German!
- [Woman] Oh, no!
- Elza, it seems to be true.
- [Sniffing]
- Mind if I smell your daughter?
- Tomoko, will you tell us
the story, okay?
So, where did
the spaceship go, then?
Uh, we don't know.
People said that it flew
very fast
and disappeared down the sky.
- With loud report.
- We only know about
the mysterious waves
that we caught.
Tomoko, come on.
- [Reporters chattering]
- You belong to the press now,
little girl.
- We'll raise you
as one of our own.
- Oh, no.
- [Chattering continues]
- Hey, what about us?
- Time to split, guys.
- I can't watch.
Uh, we, the satellite of love
wooster group,
would like to present
this week's pageant,
once again based on
a movie character's
weak resemblance
to a Hollywood star.
[Tom Servo]
Thank you, cambot.
This week, it's child star
Richard Burton,
who later went on
to star as Hamlet
at the old Vic theatre.
[Crow]
Yeah. And later
in such great films
as bluebeard, raid on rommel,
and the exorcist ii.
I will narrate,
and crow will be playing--
- crow t. Robot.
- What?
Uh, crow t. Robot.
That's my stage name.
- Oh, okay. I'm sorry. Right.
- [Scoffs]
Crow t. Robot will be playing
the part of Richard Burton,
and Thomas Servo
will play Elizabeth Taylor
and Lee majors.
I will be playing the role
of the sleepy-voiced narrator.
"Richard Burton
was born with a name
that wasn't Richard Burton,
"but we can't remember
what it was,
into a poor, Welsh,
coal-mining family in 1925."
[Crow imitating Richard Burton]
I'm Welsh. I'm poor.
My name's not
Richard Burton yet.
Do you hear me?
I'm Welsh and poor,
and my name is not
Richard Burton yet!
[Tom Servo]
Richard grew up some
and got into acting
in high school.
And then he lived
with this guy named Burton,
who gave him his name.
He particularly liked
the poetry
of his drunk, Welsh countryman,
Dylan Thomas.
[Joel]
Uh, "Richard did a radio version
of Thomas' famous adaptation
of 'the gamera song.'"
[crow imitating Richard Burton]
Not for the proud man
- ...apart from the raging moon
I write,
- [pouring drink]
- ..."gamera, gamera."
- [Ice clinking]
- What dark,
despised dreams dwell
- [pouring drink]
In the sullen weighty bones
'neath your impenetrable shell?
Ahh.
- That was good, crow.
- Ah, thanks.
No, that was really good.
- I mean, very moving.
- Joel-- Joel, please?
- [Clears throat]
- Oh, I'm sorry. Okay.
Uh, "later, Richard Burton
got famous,
"and they pay him
a lot of money
to do movies in Hollywood.
"Did some bad ones
and some good ones,
"and then he met
Elizabeth Taylor,
"and they fell in love,
and she dumped Eddie Fisher,
but he got over it
and became a really famous
chess player."
- Huh?
- "Richard and Liz
got super famous
"and became the Tom
and roseanne of their day.
"Tom Servo and crow
will now do a scene
"from their
most famous collaboration,
who's afraid
of gamera turtle?"
[Clears throat]
Arrgh! Who said that? Arrgh!
I don't know, Martha.
Oh, come on, George.
You remember.
Who said that? Arrgh!
I don't remember.
I said I do not remember,
Martha.
Oh, I remember.
It was gamera.
He walked into the room,
lit a cigarette, looked around,
and said, "arrgh!"
If you say so, Martha.
Oh, you laughed your ass off!
- That's enough, okay?
- Oh, okay.
All right. "Later,
Burton got back to his roots
"and trod the boards
as king Arthur
"in the smash musical gamera.
"His performance was
nothing less than mesmerizing,
"even when he drank two bottles
before the matinee.
Here are some highlights."
[Crow imitating Richard Burton]
Gamera, gamera...
- [Ice clinking]
- I know it sounds
a bit bizarre,
but with gamera,
that's how conditions are.
- I wonder what the king
is drinking tonight.
- [Pouring drink]
I wonder if the king
will get stinking--
okay, crow. That's enough.
[Normal voice]
I was totally off script.
Could you tell?
- I was way off--
- after the success
of gamera,
Burton's life hit a rough spot.
Parts dried up, but he didn't.
He was drinking more
and acting less.
A project called mannequin
was discussed, then dropped.
Then, just when things
were getting desperate,
his agent called.
They wanted him for a meaty role
in the critically acclaimed
television smash,
the fall guy.
"A chance to work
with Heather Thomas
and Lee majors?
"It was too good to be true.
"Burton's answer was a bleary
but resounding 'yes.'
"here we recreate a scene
from that historical
television play."
So, what do you say?
You wanna climb into my 4-by-4,
drive really fast,
help me chase down that scumbag
who jumped bail?
- What do you say?
- I say-- [hiccups]
Let's nail the sucker.
Uh, "Richard Burton
passed away shortly
"after performing
his Magnum opus.
Thus ends our pageant."
We salute you.
[All]
One of the good dead ones.
[Hiccups]
[Chuckling]
Hello, ace award.
We can't go back
to earth anymore.
I miss mother.
Don't be so cowardly.
We've got to find some way
to get out of here.
Will the caped crusader escape?
I wish gamera would come
and help us.
Why doesn't he come?
Why don't you keep quiet?
Keep quiet!
- Ooh, a little dissension
in the ranks there.
- Gamera! Gamera!
Gamera!
Boy, you know,
that really does look wet
down there, doesn't it?
- Really underwater.
- Really wet.
He is soaking down there.
Yep.
- [Growling]
- This happens to me every movie
just when I get
a little quiet time.
Those kids!
♪♪ [Dramatic soundtrack music]
♪ Doo doo doo ♪
Oh, yeah.
Tom, have you got the pistol?
Yeah, I got it.
Listen.
Shoot it at that switch.
- Oh. I see. Okay.
- Ooh.
What switch?
Save one for me
in case it doesn't work.
Rex dart: Eskimo spy.
I missed it.
- That's too bad.
- Yeah.
How many bullets
do you have left?
- Three more.
- That's pretty good!
[Yells]
Boink.
- Hey.
- Hey! Good shootin', Tex.
Hey, it's a "hands fall
in water" sign.
- [Rumbling]
- Hey, that's funny.
[Imitating Eva Gabor]
I just adore a penthouse view.
[Imitating Elvis]
Thank you. Thank you very much.
- [Imitating crowd cheering]
- Well, welcome...
[Muttering]
You hit the remote control
of guiron.
Tom, hurry.
Cut off the switch.
Okay.
[Growling]
Akio, what should we do?
Try to get out, baldy.
[Tom Servo chuckles]
Let's play "cuts like a knife."
Oh, no. Look.
They're playing space-age
at-home wheel of fortune there.
It's working now.
That's because
it's Fisher-price.
- [Guiron growling]
- Hmm?
- Right. It's guiron.
- I wonder what happened.
We are in trouble.
It's impossible
to control from here.
There is no other way.
Let's escape to the earth.
- Our flight is one of danger.
- What are we gonna do
with those kids?
- Leave them here.
- How much is that doggie
in the window?
Come on. Hurry.
You know, that thing has
the fins of a '57 dodge.
- Uh-oh.
- He thinks it's a frisbee!
- Oh, no!
- Down, boy. Bad. Bad.
[Women grunting]
- Ooh.
- Oh!
- My legs!
- They're great.
- Hey.
- I can't go to earth anymore.
What shall I do?
- Wait.
- What's the matter?
- Oh. It hurts.
- I've got a football
on my head.
I can't move. Help me.
- Uhh...
- Okay. Never mind.
Florbella!
On our planet,
useless members
are supposed to die.
Say...
- Could we send
Dan quayle there?
- Ooh.
She had to put her down.
Uh-huh.
Hey, cleans up in a jiffy.
The invaders, in color.
We're in trouble.
Guiron is coming nearer.
- So what else is new?
- It's the end. We'll be killed.
[Boys shouting]
Help! Help!
[Tom Servo]
♪ oh, slice of the knife and a ♪
♪♪ [humming]
It's mack the forehead.
[Laughs]
- ♪ Yep, hittin' the thing ♪
- [shouting continues]
Don't you know
you're only annoying him?
Oh, well, they got
the cable back on.
- Thanks.
- Cool.
- Gamera!
- Gamera! Gamera, help us!
- It's only Patrick Swayze
films.
- Help us, gamera!
- [Mock grunt]
- Come on!
- All right, all right!
I'm up!
- Gamera!
- Help us, gamera! Come on!
[Growling]
- Don't quit.
- [Mock grunt]
- Come on. Four.
- Come on. Five.
- [Mock grunt]
Feel the burn.
Come on. One more.
Just 15 more reps,
gamera. Come on.
- Gotta want it.
- Go for the burn.
Come on. Do it.
- Have some heart.
Dig, dig, dig!
- Gamera!
Come on, gamera!
Come on!
Get up!
- [Shouting]
- Oops.
You know, this is just
like Hamlet-- everybody dies.
There are many parallels--
what are you talking about?
[Shouting]
So it's really wet there.
♪♪ [Humming]
♪ I'm gonna do some slicin'
and a-dicin' ♪
- ♪ choppin' and a... ♪
- [Thudding]
[Thudding]
- Uh-oh.
- Okay. That's it.
I'm up.
- Uh-oh.
- [Thudding]
Uugh!
- Ooh!
- Oh!
He took that one
right on the chin.
- [Screeches]
- Hmm?
- He sounds like a cat.
- [Screeching]
He's a turtle cat.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
They just invented the world's
largest orange Julius.
- Tom, are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
We're having an adventure
which can be compared
to one of the goonies.
[Water splashing]
- Look. It's gamera.
- Down, boy.
Gotta go. See ya.
Bye.
Huh?
- Back. Fooled ya. [Laughs]
- Whoo.
♪♪ [Dramatic soundtrack music]
♪♪ [Tom Servo imitating
dramatic soundtrack music]
Flying low.
[Growling]
Ooh.
Gamera!
Gamera, get him!
Kill him!
Kill it, gamera!
Yes, dear, I'm doing it.
How can I do it
if you keep yelling at me?
Hooray!
Nice job. A success.
[Growling, roaring]
[With brogue]
Come on, boy.
[Laughs]
Ain't that like a dago?
Brings a knife to a gunfight.
Sean Connery.
- [Mutters]
- [Laughing]
Now you're just
tempering my blade.
Ha!
It's no good.
Gamera's jet propulsion--
it's no good up front.
It's good in the back.
[Chuckles]
Now, this turtle--
he's kooky.
- Huh?
- Going down.
[Screeching]
[Laughs]
Some of these tricks
are meant for me, folks.
I love it.
Gym...kata!
[Laughs]
Hooray!
That's good, gamera!
Keep on going!
- Doink.
- Huh?
Huh?
Oh, yeah.
Just like Mitch gaylord
in American anthem here, huh?
Yeah. Kind of like
vision quest too.
[Laughs]
This is rich.
Yeah. That's Cathy rigby
in that suit.
[Chuckling]
Think so?
- [Mock grunting]
- You know, guys?
- Hmm?
- It just dawned on me
how weird this film is,
you know?
- Yeah.
- Really?
- It's kind of goofy.
- Is it? Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Oh, nice dismount.
- Judges like it.
- East German gave him a 9.
- Oh! I forgot about those!
- [Screeching]
- Oh!
- [Screeching continues]
Owie! Owie!
Hey, it looks like
he's playing "oh! Susanna."
♪ With a banjo on his knee ♪
[Guffaws]
Hey, look at gamera.
He's dancing go-go.
- "Dancing go-go"?
- No.
He's trying to get rid
of those metal things.
He can't pull his feet in
with them.
Well, whatever.
I just really like it.
And he can't work
his jet propulsion.
What'll he do?
[Gasps]
Oh, no! It's a pool!
- Of filth! Ooh!
- Watch out!
Guiron is coming this way!
Tom, hurry!
Find the remote control switch.
So, he's coming this way, then?
- From what I've been told,
yes. Hello.
- Please hurry!
- Thank you.
- Hurry. Come on.
[Buttons clicking]
Okay, what's the password,
"swordfish"?
Aye.
Huh?
[All]
♪ da-da-da-da da-da ♪
♪ waahh ♪
So this the end of us.
It makes me mad.
- If we only had a weapon--
- a brain.
- ...i could destroy him.
- [Joel mutters]
- Akio, wishful thinking
is no good.
- Wait.
[Buttons clacking]
Dear Judy...
Oh. Okay. I'll start over.
Never mind.
[Tom Servo]
♪ doo doo doo doo ♪
This really makes me mad.
- This will be the last way.
- [Tom Servo chuckles]
I'll get 'em this time.
- She sounds like
she's from Indiana.
- [Screeching]
- Boy, is he wet.
- Very wet.
[Screeching continues]
Oh, I hate this part.
I can't stand
when they show that.
- It's okay.
It'll be over soon, Joel.
- Ehh.
Ooh, that hurts.
Bite a bullet or something.
Ohh, yeah!
Oh, that's good.
That feels better. Whew.
- [Crashing]
- Whoa!
- I have to be
especially careful,
for I have no hair.
- Uh-oh.
- [Screaming, grunting]
[Imitating Richard Burton]
Oh, I must've had
six bottles last night.
- [Whirring]
- Uh-oh.
- [Boys] Huh?
- [Mock gulp]
Wow. What's that?
Looks like the missile
from scene 14.
- It is.
- Hey.
Akio, maybe it's that weapon
you've been looking for.
- Akio, it's a missile.
- Right.
- Is he gonna worship
the missile now?
- This must be the Gauge.
- I need more toot.
- Peruvian blow for me.
- Thanks, mister.
- Way to blow, kid.
Whoa. Better call the pound.
[Crow whistling dog call]
[Tom Servo whistling dog call]
[Whistling continues]
[Joel mutters]
- Hey.
- [Screeching]
Okay, who am I?
Who am I?
Creature from the black lagoon!
- I was gonna guess diver Dan.
- Mm.
Look out. He's got
his oyster knife at the ready.
Doh!
[Screeching continues]
- Uh-oh.
- Ooh, right in the hinders.
Oh!
That hurt.
Ooh.
Oh, he's gonna use him
as a kickboard.
Mm.
Wasn't expecting this.
- Wheeee!
- Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Errr.
Tom, gamera is coming out!
- [Water splashing]
- Look!
- Hey, maybe he can help
clean up some of the styrofoam.
- Yeah.
Whoa!
Going up.
[All]
Whoa!
Fun.
Oh, he's playing
supersonic mumblepeg!
- [Sputtering]
- Huh?
- Even we are surprised.
- [Boys cheering]
- And there was much rejoicing.
- [Tom Servo] Boo!
[Joel]
Yay!
[Boys continue cheering]
He will remain here
as a constant reminder
of the horror
that took place here.
- Tom, now.
- Here. Thank you.
That's gotta be, like,
tackle record of the century!
Whoa.
Uh, kids,
don't play with missiles.
- Not a good idea.
- [Grunting]
Ohhh!
Oh, look. Just as she had
a call coming in.
Why don't you just
f-f-fade away?
Huh?
Neat.
[Gamera screeching]
Ooh!
- Haikeeba!
- [Yells]
Gamera, guiron's weak part
is the hole.
Get that hole!
- Yeah, yeah.
- You said it.
Oh, damn.
- Whoa!
- Hurts, don't it?
[Growls]
[Mock growls]
God, this bites.
He was a good friend.
[Together]
You got him!
- [Screeches]
- Yeah, I got him.
- Thanks a lot.
- Banzai.
- Whoo!
- Thanks a lot.
- I'm the one.
- [Whistling]
- It's me.
- [Akio mutters]
I know.
He beckons.
Gamera beckons.
- Huh?
- Fixin's a snap
with krazy glue.
- [Whooshing]
- Look, gamera's repairing
the spaceship.
Yeah, I, uh, took oxy-acetylene
welding at vo-tech.
Tom, gamera is waiting.
- Okay.
- ♪♪ [Tom Servo humming along
with soundtrack music]
- ♪♪ [Whistling]
- Stopping at amityville,
copiague,
lindenhurst, Babylon,
change in Jamaica.
[Joel]
♪ we're in a cheesy ♪
[Joel, Tom Servo]
♪ special effect ♪
♪♪ [Tom Servo continues humming]
♪♪ [Crow whistling]
- Let's go.
- Okay.
[Tom Servo]
♪ the kids marching... ♪
[Gamera's jet propulsion blasts]
- Huh?
- Whoa.
Soft mouth, boy!
Soft mouth!
- There you go.
Gamera's a domino's dude now.
- They'll probably be home
in 30 minutes or less.
- Hey, it's moving.
- Hooray!
- Now we can go
back to earth again.
- We're so lucky.
- You know what I want?
- A donut!
- Doh!
- [Children] ♪ gamera ♪
- [all laughing]
- ♪ Gamera ♪
- [all] ♪ gamera ♪
- ♪♪ [continues in Japanese]
- ♪ gamera is filled with meat ♪
♪ we are eating gamera ♪
- [Children shouting]
- One, two, three, four,
tell the people what she wore!
- ♪♪ [Children singing
in Japanese]
- [Joel] ♪ gamera ♪
♪♪ [crow singing in Japanese]
I am a fan of the original
Japanese version myself.
♪ I hope I can get
this tune out of my head ♪
- [Joel] Yeah!
- ♪♪ [Tom Servo humming]
Isn't this the song
from Oliver, though?
Kind of sounds like it--
"food, glorious food."
♪♪ [Whistling along]
♪ We believe in gamera ♪
Hey!
- Meat.
- Huh?
Oh, she was the jackal.
Oh.
There's a bunch of kids
singing up there.
- This will never do.
- ♪♪ [upbeat soundtrack music]
Oh, no!
It's a Mark Russell song! Run!
Hey, she's got that
Charlie's angels' run
down really good.
- Yeah.
- Stop her!
She's got my keyboard!
- Huh?
- It's obscure.
- Very.
- Oh.
Cornjob, quick!
Hey! Hey, listen!
Listen!
What's the matter?
Is there anything wrong?
It's about gamera.
I must make a report about it.
And stop bothering me
until I finish my report.
- [Ringing]
- And quit wearing my clothes.
- Hello. Shiga speaking.
- Yes?
Yes, I know.
I haven't been in this film.
Yes, I know. I've been busy.
- I can't believe it.
- I know. Yes.
- Thank you.
- Doctor, I saw gamera
on our telescope.
And I saw gamera
kissing Santa claus.
He was carrying
the ship in his mouth.
- What a dish.
- Nice dish.
- [Laughs, mutters]
- What a dish.
Yeah.
- Hey, they're driving
a Mercedes.
- Huh.
[People chattering]
- L.l. Bean rhubarb.
- Eddie Bauer rhubarb.
[Mock chatter]
J. Crew rhubarb.
Penny's rhubarb.
[Mock chatter continues]
- Botany 500 rhubarb.
- Channel 9 rhubarb.
- It's almost unbelievable.
- Nuclear family rhubarb.
But the boys were taken
exactly from here.
- It's pretty hard to believe.
- You better believe it.
- Or you're dead where ya stand.
- Tomoko is right.
When the whip comes down,
you will see who rules,
you twisted old fruit.
- Gentlemen, please believe
tomoko's story.
- Hey.
You know, gamera is
a good friend of hers.
- It is.
- Kill him.
- Kon-chan?
- Huh? What, tomoko?
- [Joel whispering] They will
all die by gamera's hand.
- Thank you.
That's okay, tomoko.
- Oh, god, the Germans are here!
- [Chattering]
Well, they can sort it
all out.
[Imitating Ricardo montalban]
Smiles, everyone! Smiles!
- Where's the place?
- We're from
the padding department.
- Where's the plot hole?
- Thank you.
They've got the end
of the police there.
- Why, you must be
the two boys' mothers.
- Yes.
- I'm akio's mother.
- I'm glad to know you.
It's unbelievable,
but gamera is heading this way
with a spaceship...
In his mouth!
Can you beat that?
'Cause you could've knocked me
over with a feather!
- Whoa!
- [Tomoko] Look, it's gamera!
- Well, it's about time.
- [People exclaiming]
♪♪ ["Gamera's theme"]
[Joel, high-pitched voice]
I'm first! I wish to be
the first to be crushed!
Aahh!
- Wait, honey. He's a film.
He's just a film.
- Brother!
Elza, it's hard to believe,
but we really should've
believed our children.
- [Tom Servo scoffs]
- I'm still gonna spank him.
[Elza mutters]
- Brother!
- Tomoko!
Are you all right?
We have been so worried.
- I'm okay.
- [Tom Servo guffawing]
- Hey, your glasses.
- My glasses?
It's all right.
You know, when I'm happy,
my glasses--
they always come down.
- [Laughter]
- And so do my pants.
Gamera!
- Sorry about your breath!
- [Growling]
- I know, I know.
- Mother!
- I'm glad you are safe.
- Everybody grab a kid.
- Mm-hmm.
- Are you really okay?
But listen, akio,
you have made everybody worry.
- Mm.
- Uh-oh.
Mother, ma'am,
everybody, we're awfully sorry.
- Doh!
- Hey!
Akio, you shaved your head
before I could do it, huh?
- Huh?
- The spacemen--
they shaved it off.
- Is that right?
- Listen. Listen.
- Huh?
- Kon-chan--
- hey, that's dirty!
- ...There are spacemen,
too, like you.
- Right, kon-chan?
- [Laughter]
- [Mock laughs]
- That's cornjob!
- [All laugh]
- Dr. Shiga,
we discovered a planet
- ...and saw space people too.
- Look at that kid. He's got
a couple of divots in his head.
- He must've had an older
brother with a class ring.
- Yeah.
- That's what happened.
- ...More than the earth
where we are living now.
- But, as a result,
I like earth best.
- Mm-hmm.
Dr. Shiga,
we belong to the earth.
He's a skinhead now.
He's gonna go throw
a chair at Geraldo.
- Let's make the earth
a free place to live--
- uh-huh.
...without war
and traffic accidents--
[Joel, robots]
What is with
the traffic accidents?
[Crow] For crying out loud!
[Scoffs]
- Oh, that was
a very good experience.
- Yes, sir.
- What a kiss-up! Cripes!
- [Growls]
- Gamera's taking off.
- ♪♪ ["gamera's theme"]
[Spoken lyrics]
Gamera, hey.
- Oh, you crazy gamera cat now.
- Thank you, gamera!
- Oh, oh, gamera,
full of meat.
- Bye!
- Hey, really neat.
- [Kids] Bye, gamera!
- I'm digging gamera baby!
- Good-bye, gamera!
- Well, there he goes.
- [Crow] Yeah, bye-bye.
- Good-bye, gamera! Good-bye!
- Well, let's roll, guys.
- Yeah, whatever, kids.
- Come on.
- Call me next time
you hijack a spaceship.
- Good-bye!
- What is this,
the long goodbye?
- That one stung, huh? Mm.
- Yeah.
[Children]
Gamera, good-bye!
[Crow shouts]
♪ Gamera ♪
♪ gamera ♪
♪ hirohito gamera ♪
[Shouting]
♪♪ [All singing in Japanese]
- Go, go, go!
- Whoo!
♪♪ [Singing resumes]
Cornjob!
♪ Hirohito gamera ♪
♪ hirohito gamera ♪
- What do you think, sirs?
- Whoo!
♪♪ [Piano]
Anyway, he got his start
getting cigarettes
for Agnes de Mille,
if you can believe that.
But, anyway,
back to my original story,
which was that it seems
that Oscar hammerstein
spent two weeks
up at his buck county farm
writing the lyrics to
"oh, what a beautiful morning."
And he labored over it.
And then he turns it over
to dick Rodgers,
who sits down and promptly--
in ten minutes, mind you--
writes the melody.
And I don't have to
tell you two gentlemen
that American musical theater
was never quite the same thing.
What a wonderful story.
Uh, tell us that story
about Cole Porter again.
- Oh, please do.
- Should I? Really? Okay.
Well, Cole Porter, during
his horse-riding accident--
well, he was laying
in the middle of the woods
with his legs crushed,
yelling for help.
He decided to write
"at long last love."
- Oh, no!
- That's a true story.
But what a lot of people
don't know
is that the lyrics were altered
for its Broadway opening, yes.
And the original lyrics
went something like this.
Very tender.
- Oh, my god!
I'm in so much pain!
- ♪♪ [discordant notes]
Somebody please help me!
Somebody come and save me!
What an enchanting anecdote.
- They don't write them
like that anymore, do they?
- They certainly do not.
How does the gamera theme song
stack up against songs
from yesteryear?
Oh, well, it's interesting
that you ask that,
because the opening lyric
of the gamera song
has sort of
a Rodgers and hart feel to it.
Let me show you what I mean.
♪ Gamera ♪
♪ gamera ♪
♪ gamera is really neat ♪
♪ gamera is filled with meat ♪
♪ we all love you, gamera ♪
But then the second part
is a little more fun.
It has a sort of George
and ira gershwin feel to it.
♪ Shell, teeth,
eyes, claws ♪
♪ scales, breath, fun ♪
It sort of sneaks up on you.
"Boo," it says.
♪ Gamera's enchantment
still grows ♪
♪ he fills our hearts
with love ♪
♪ gamera's the latest thing ♪
♪ he fills our hearts
with spring, spring, spring ♪
♪ anytime you want
some moonbeams ♪
♪ gamera is the thing ♪
♪ gamera is really neat ♪
♪ he is filled
with turtle meat ♪
♪ we all love you, gamera ♪
- Ah. Kill him.
- Yeah.
Better yet, I'll kill him.
You push the button.
♪♪ [Piano]
- What a monster.
- Yeah.